ABBAS PARYAVI

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

P (202) 805-8280

E abbparyavi@gmail.com A Potomac, MD 20854





abbasparyavi.com

OBJECTIVE

Junior Software Engineer with over 4 years of experience and a passion in software development and application integration. Majority of experience has been in full stack development using React, PostgreSQL, Node Js, and Azure VMs. Extensive experience in web hosting, application integration, and creating servers, VMs, and databases.

EXPERIENCE

Jun 2021 - Present

Full Stack Developer – International Data Center Authority (IDCA)

- Developed an in-house web application which includes a full CMS for admin access, user portal with event and course registration capabilities, and a membership platform.
- Integrated an open-source forum application (NodeBB) onto the membership platform running on Azure VM.
- Integrated Zoom registration and emailing capabilities with event registration saving 15 hours of monthly manual work from employees.
- Setup and integrated Salesforce CRM for sales representatives and MarketingCloud for email marketing purposes.
 - Customized lead, contact, and opportunity objects for salesforce users, and automated reporting for sales representatives.
 - Automated MarketingCloud email subscriber lists based on demographics and other criteria.
- Tools: React, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Node JS, Express JS, Azure VM, Azure Functions, Firebase, Firebase Cloud Functions, GitHub, REST APIs, and Salesforce

Aug 2020 - Jan 2021

Data Science Research Assistant – UMD CS Department

- Analyzed and rendered the computer science building's collected data, to ensure that the air conditioning systems as well as the lighting systems operate more efficiently.
- Tools: Python, NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib

Jul 2019 - Nov 2019

Data Center Engineering Intern – TechXact Group Corporation

- Audited IOT's (Indiana Office of Technology) three main data center infrastructures finding numerous design and implementation flaws by shadowing expert auditors.
- Assisted with technical content development and editing of one of the engineering courses.

EDUCATION

University of Maryland, College Park. MD | 3.7GPA

Computer Engineer | May 2023

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGUES

- **JAVASCRIPT**
- PYTHON (PANDAS, NUMPY, SELENIUM, FLASK, MATPLOTLIB)
- **JAVA**

OTHER RELATED SKILLS

- **REACT**
- **AZURE VM**
- **AZURE FUNCTIONS**
- WEB DEVELOPMENT
- **WEB HOSTING**
- **REST API**
- **POSTGRESQL**
- **MONGODB**
- LINUX
- **DOCKER**
- HTML
- CSS
- NODE IS
- **EXPRESS IS**
- MACHINE LEARNING
- **DATA SCIENCE**

AWARDS

- NATIONAL SOCIETY OF **COLLEGIATE SCHOLARS MEMBER**
- DR. HARRY HARDEN JR. STUDENT ACADEMIC **EXCELLENCE AWARDS**
- 4.0 STUDENT AT MONTGOMERY COLLEGE, CONSECUTIVELY ON **DEAN'S LIST**
- MEN'S U-20 TABLE TENNIS US **OPEN 2019 FINALIST**